你是谁
Who are you?
你干什么呢  快出去
What are you doing? Get out of here!
妈妈
Mom!
卢  卢
Lue? Lue?
你没事吧
You okay?
没事的  亲爱的
Okay, honey.
放松  没事的
Calm down. It's all right.
只是一个噩梦
You're just having another bad dream.
我喘不上气了
I can't breathe!
你能呼吸的
Yes, you can.
没事的  放松
You're fine. Just relax.
慢慢地做个深呼吸
Just take slow, deep breaths.
慢慢的
Nice and easy.
没什么可怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
我在  使劲呼吸  但是不行
I'm...trying... but I can't!
放松
Relax.
慢慢来个深呼吸
Slow, deep breaths.
不行啊
I...can't.
卢
Lue?
天啊  卢
Oh, my god. Lue?
卢  醒醒
Lue, wake up!
醒醒  卢  快醒醒
Wake up, lue! Come on!
卢
Lue!
总监：
zlean
我呼你都有两个多小时了
Been paging you for over two hours.
我一定是在洗澡
I must've been in the shower.
之后我还得再保湿一下
Then I had to moisturize.
一个八岁的男孩昨晚被送进急诊室
Eight-year-old boy was brought into the ER
有急性呼吸窘迫综合征
last night with acute respiratory distress.
没有...
No history of--
没有哮喘和过敏病史
No histories of asthma or allergies,
胸片未见异常
and his chest x-ray's clear.
其实  我做了两回保湿
Actually, I had to moisturize twice.
多米尼卡昨晚做了焗牡蛎
Dominika made Oysters Rockefeller last night.
那孩子做了个噩梦
Kid's been having night terrors,
醒来后呼吸完全停止
woke up in the middle of one in full respiratory arrest.
由压力诱发的惊恐发作
Stress-induced panic attack.
告诉他父母别给孩子太大压力
Tell the parents to lay off the grades.
以后做个厨子也挺好
The world needs fry cooks too.
这孩子成绩很好
Does great in school.
父母离异  但家庭还算和睦
The parents are divorced, but it was amicable.
他爸爸搬到别的州了
And the dad's moved out of state.
你看见威尔森了吗
Have you seen Wilson around?
他梦见  有一个又老又丑的巫婆
The dreams are about an ugly, old hag
想掐死他
trying to strangle him.
他们是苗族人
The family's Hmong.
夜死症
SUNS--
夜间猝死综合征
Sudden unexpected nocturnal death syndrome,
也就是说没人知道病人是怎么死的
aka bs name for no one's figured out why they died.
在八十年代初发生一百多例
Over 100 in the early '80s.
都是男性  皆为苗族
Only male, only hmong.
直到在睡眠中死去
Healthy right up until the moment
他们的身体都非常健康
they died in their sleep.
-他做什么梦了  -这没关系吧
- What was he dreaming about? - It doesn't matter.
只是一个梦
It's a dream.
没什么特殊意义
It doesn't mean anything.
如果噩梦足够吓人
If the nightmare's scary enough,
不管有没有意义  都可能引起儿茶酚胺激增
meaningful or not, it could cause a catecholamine surge
还有心室纤颤
and ventricular fibrillation.
一个远古恶魔
An ancient demon called a Dab
坐在他旁边  想掐死他
was sitting on him, strangling him.
这够吓人的
I think that qualifies.
但根据其它检查结果
Except in the rational part of the file,
他的心电图正常
where it says his EKG's within normal limits.
不是心脏问题
It's not his heart.
会不会是阻塞性睡眠呼吸暂停
What about obstructive sleep apnea?
阻塞性睡眠呼吸暂停不会导致在他醒后
Sleep apnea wouldn't have caused breathing problems
还无法呼吸
after he woke up.
你梦见了什么
What did you dream of?
我从来都记不住我做过什么梦
I never remember my dreams.
但你很肯定它们都没什么意义
But you're certain that they're insignificant,
带着辩护的语气
defensively so.
我是在为科学辩护
I was defending science.
你用辩护的语气辩护科学
You were defensively defending science.
吸入有毒物质所致的肺损伤
Lung damage from inhaled toxins
可能引起他在醒后还无法呼吸
could keep causing problems after he woke up.
或者是上呼吸道感染
Or an upper respiratory infection.
好吧  奇斯和朴克
Okay, Chase and Park,
给他挂上抗生素治疗肺炎
start IV antibiotics for pneumonia.
陶博和亚当斯去他家看看有什么有毒物质
Taub and Adams, go check the home for toxins.
我能和陶博一起么
Could I go with Taub?
那是我的主意
It was my idea.
这样...  因为就那么一刹那
Right... 'cause for a moment there,
我还以为你是不想和奇斯在一块
I thought you were uncomfortable around Chase
因为你梦见个澳大利亚帅哥
because you'd had a nocturnal Australian.
你想和谁搭档都行
You can go with whoever you want.
但你们所有人  都得把这些病例看完
But all of you, read all of these files.
你认为是恶灵在伤害你儿子吗
Do you believe a spirit could be hurting your son?
当然不
No, of course not.
因为如果他从小就被灌输这类信仰
Because if he's been taught to believe that,
就有可能是巨大的恐惧
it is possible for the fear alone
影响到他的心脏功能
to affect heart function.
我是名工程师
I'm an engineer.
我知道恶灵是无法带来疾病的
I know illnesses aren't caused by evil spirits.
抱歉  我不是有意的
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to,
我只是得  问一下
I just... had to check.
你还有别的事要问吗
Anything else you need to check?
没了
No.
我做了个梦
I had a dream.
豪斯
House...
我们稍后再谈
We can talk later.
别紧张  我是医生
Relax, I'm a doctor.
你完美的胸部对我来说不算什么
Your spectacular breasts mean nothing to me.
豪斯
House...
House!
等会再说
Later.
我和多米尼卡上床了
I had sex with Dominika.
在梦里吗
In a dream?
不是真正的做爱
It wasn't literally sex.
严格点说  算是口交
Technically, it was flossing.
你懂的  牙齿碰蛋蛋
You know, teeth, testicles.
我说的够明白了吧
I think the symbolism is pretty clear.
"等会再说"升级为"永不提起"
"Later" just changed to "Never."
我告诉你什么更奇怪吧
I'll tell you what would be weirder,
那就是你没梦见过和奇斯上床
if you didn't dream about having sex with Chase.
你梦见过吗
Have you?
没有
No.
但是我梦见过
But I've dreamed about having sex
和很多同事上床
with a lot of people I work with,
并不觉得有啥奇怪
and it didn't freak me out.
那不一样
That's different.
怎么不一样
How?
因为你本身就和
'Cause you've actually had sex
很多同事上过床
with a lot of people at work,
那都不足为奇了  春梦算什么
and that hasn't freaked you out.
有道理
Good point.
那你是在担心这个梦的意义吗
So you're worried about what it means?
我没担心  这梦没啥意义
I'm not worried. It means nothing.
还是有些意义的  对吗
It means something, doesn't it?
他是我同事
I work with him.
我不能想和他滚床单
I can't want to sleep with him.
也许奇斯只代表了工作
Maybe Chase just represents work.
你只是爱上你的工作罢了
You're just falling in love with your job.
最近倒是确实挺开心的
It has been very satisfying lately.
你闻到了吗
You smell that?
闻到了  像是湿了的狗
Yeah. Smells like wet dog.
是霉
It's mold.
-不是霉  -肯定是霉
- It's not mold. - It's definitely mold.
看不出有任何漏水迹象
I don't see any sign of water damage.
天呐
Holy crap.
那感觉就像进了屠宰场
It looked like a slaughterhouse.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我们走的时候还好好的
It was clean when we left.
这么说有人闯入你们家
You're telling us some random person broke into your house
就为在你儿子的房间里肢解一头猪吗
to dismember a pig in your son's bedroom?
一头猪
A pig?
是我公公
My father-in-law.
你到底干了什么
What did you do?
早在几周前  噩梦开始时
What you should have done weeks ago,
你就该做的事
when the dreams started.
我在救卢
I'm saving Lue.
他的心搏停止了
He's coding!
这里需要一位医生
Need a doctor in here!
室速  无脉搏
V-tach. No pulse.
-天哪  -静推1毫克肾上腺素
- Oh, my god! - Push 1 milligram epi!
-准备电极  充电50焦耳  -充电
- Paddles. Charge to 50. - Charging!
离手
Clear!
宝贝
Baby...
仍为室速
Still v-tach!
充电100焦耳
Charge to 100!
100焦耳
100!
远离病床
Clear!
-充电...  -等等
- Charge-- - wait!
正常窦性心律
Normal sinus rhythm.
我的天
Oh, god!
目前他还稳定
He's stable,
但显然又增加了一个症状
but we've obviously got a second symptom.
嗯嗯嗯  小孩室速
Yeah, yeah, yeah, kid in v-tach.
说说他屋里的那个夏威夷野猪宴
Tell me about the luau in his bedroom.
是苗族的一种传统仪式
It's a traditional Hmong ceremony
说是能召回那孩子的灵魂
that's supposed to call back the kid's soul.
-他没听说过呼叫返回吗  -不只这样
- Hasn't he heard of star-6-9? - There's more.
爷爷之所以会认为小孩的灵魂被偷了
The reason grandpa thinks the kid's soul is stolen
是因为他确信自己的儿子
is because he's convinced his son,
那孩子父亲的灵魂也被偷走过
the kid's father, had his stolen as well.
他把他的老板活活打死了
He beat his boss to death.
爸爸并不是搬了家
The dad didn't move away.
是进了监狱
He's in prison.
创伤后应激障碍很有可能
PTSD could definitely cause
导致呼吸问题
breathing problems--
这不是创伤后应激障碍
It's not PTSD.
就算当时那孩子不在场
Even if the kid wasn't there,
仅仅是听说了他爸爸的事
just hearing what the dad did...
他并不知道
But he hasn't.
当时他才两岁
It happened when he was two,
他一直以为
and all he's ever been told is that
父母离了婚
his parents divorced
而爸爸搬走了
and his dad moved away.
心脏骤停表示恶性心律失常
The heart thing indicates a malignant arrhythmia.
需要为他行心脏电生理学检查
He needs an E.P. Study.
其他病例里有多少人
How many of the other files
出现过恶性心律失常的症状
showed malignant arrhythmias?
都没有  不过
None, but--
不做电生理学
Forget the E.P.
有急性心包炎的可能吗
What about acute pericarditis?
可以解释他的呼吸困难
Explains the dyspnea.
病例里有多少...
How many of the other files...
仰卧位时症状加重
It's exacerbated by lying supine,
在他睡觉的时候
so the symptoms would get worse
症状就会恶化
when he goes to sleep.
就和其他100多个病例一样
Just like all 100 of the others.
做超声检查心包
Do an echo to check the pericardium.
看看你能否在样本里
See if you can find any cardioactive toxins
找出任何刺激心脏的毒素
in the home samples.
我想说  我真的非常喜欢我的工作
Can I just say that I very much enjoy my job?
不  不  别这样
No, no, please.
没必要为你之前的态度道歉
No need to apologize for your earlier behavior.
那个梦还是薄荷味的
Floss was mint.
大概是因为她在浴室里
Probably because of this green g-string
晾了条绿色丁字裤的关系
she hangs up to dry in the bathroom.
我的手表一定是停了
My watch must have stopped.
显然"永不"已经到了
Apparently it's already "never."
你最好暂时把电话设为呼叫转移
You might want to forward your calls.
你是绝不会想听
You do not want
我绘声绘色的描述
the Reader's Digest version on this.
她穿着非常紧身的牙医制服
There was a very tight hygienist's uniform,
略带挑逗性地用着喷壶
suggestive use of the water sprayer.
你的春梦并不代表性  是内疚
The floss isn't sex. It's guilt.
你把多米尼卡
It's tying you up for
获得身份的通知扔了
throwing away the I.N.S. notification
所以感到内疚
granting Dominika her citizenship.
她能搬走了  自己却还不知道
She can move out, but she still doesn't know it,
基本上就等于你把她给关了起来
which means you're basically holding her prisoner.
把实话告诉她
Tell her the truth,
别再来烦我
and leave me alone.
-真的吗  -怎么啦
- Really? - What?
你吓了我一跳
You startled me.
我们每天都在一起工作
We work together every day,
常常处于压力之下
usually under a fair amount of stress.
我偶尔出现在
It's only natural I'd pop into
你的潜意识里是很自然的事
a subconscious thought every once in a while.
你梦见过和我上床吗
Have you ever dreamt about having sex with me?
没有
No.
你犹豫了
You paused.
不  我没有  你觉得我是在说谎吗
No, I didn't. You think I'm lying?
不  我认为你是怕自己回答得太快
No, I think you're fighting the urge to snap
因为你的潜意识
the word "no" because
其实觉得这想法很荒唐
your subconscious finds the idea abhorrent.
若我立刻回答  会冒犯你
So if I snap, it's offensive,
如果我稍有停顿  也会因为
and if I don't snap, it's offensive
同样的原因冒犯你
for the exact same reason?
和你的潜意识谈谈吧
Talk to your subconscious.
现在变得尴尬  也是因为你弄尴尬的
This is becoming weird because you're making it weird.
你想说你没觉得这想法很荒唐吗
So you don't find the idea abhorrent?
我和你一起共事
I work with you.
没必要回答这个问题
I don't have to answer that question.
你刚刚就算是回答了
You just did.
发生什么事了
What happened?
超声无异常
Echo was negative,
但是他有剧烈的腹痛
but he has severe abdominal pain.
超声检查未见肠梗阻征象
Ultrasound didn't suggest any intestinal blockages,
不过便秘很严重
but he's severely constipated.
从厨房取的样本中没查出芽孢杆菌属
No spores, clostridium, or organic toxins
梭菌属及有机毒素  卧室里也没有
in the kitchen samples. Nothing in the bedroom either.
应行肠镜检查
We need to scope him,
需要先为他灌肠
and we're gonna need to clear his bowel first.
应该行甲状腺活检
We should biopsy his thyroid.
他可是便秘
For an impacted bowel?
桥本甲状腺炎可以解释其
Hashimoto's thyroiditis would explain
肺  心及肠道受累
his lung, heart, and intestinal involvement.
如果你认为这还不够得到豪斯的批准
And if you think we still need House's approval,
这也能解释在睡眠中死亡
it also explains dying in your sleep.
好主意
Nice call.
你说请我吃饭
When you invite me for dinner,
我还以为你会带我去餐馆
I thought maybe you take me to a restaurant.
至少会有盘子
Or have plates.
对不起
Yeah, sorry.
那个送外卖的笨蛋忘记带来了
Idiot delivery guy forgot them.
是送外卖的笨蛋
The idiot delivery guy,
还是那个把饭放在休息室冰箱里
or the idiot guy whose food you stole
却被你偷了的笨蛋
from lounge refrigerator?
你还真了解我
You've gotten to know me pretty well.
我的绿卡全指望这个了  是吧
My citizenship depends on it, right?
是的
Yeah.
其实我想和你谈谈这事
That's actually why I wanted to talk to you.
有消息了吗
You heard news?
是的
Yeah.
怎么说
So what news?
还要我们去做个面试吗
They want us to come in for another interview?
不用
No.
因为一直没动静
Since we hadn't heard anything,
我就打电话去问了
I--I called, and they said
他们说还要几个星期
it's gonna be a couple weeks,
也可能要一个月才能出最终结果
maybe a month till they finalize their decision.
要一个月
A month?
是啊  太糟了
Yeah, I know. It sucks.
没有  和你生活一点也不糟
No, it's--it's not suck to live with you.
我过得很开心  只是...
It's been fun, but...
我希望能成为合法公民
you know, I just want to be legal.
你会的
And you will be.
没问题的
Absolutely.
话说回来
In the meantime,
你玩过射击吗
you ever shot anyone?
别过来
No, get away.
你瞧  这针头还没你
Look, this needle isn't nearly
手臂上插着的那根粗呢
as big as the one in your arm.
插那根的时候都不疼  是吧
And that didn't hurt, did it?
我就是不要
I don't want it.
他们必须这么做  卢
They need to do it, Lue.
就是打麻药的时候会有些疼
You'll only feel a little pinch as we give you the numbing medicine,
之后  就不觉得疼了
and after that, you won't feel a thing.
不要
No!
卢  冷静下  没事的
Lue, calm down. It's gonna be okay.
他在说什么
What's he saying?
-怎么了  -我不知道
- What's the problem? - I don't know.
他是说  太晚了
He's saying it's too late.
一切无法挽回了
There's nothing we can do.
是苗语
It's Hmong.
他不会说苗语
He doesn't speak Hmong.
连听也没听过
He's never even heard it.
不是他在说
It isn't him speaking.
是恶魔在说
It's the Dab.
他抽搐了
He's seizing!
我的天啊
Oh--! Oh, my god!
这里需要劳拉西泮
Need some Lorazepam in here!
抽搐可排除桥本甲状腺炎
Seizure rules out Hashimoto's.
对  这才是重点
Yeah, that's the issue.
而不是我们没有一个合理的解释能说通
Not that we have no rational explanation
为什么病人会说一种他从未听过的语言
for how the patient spoke a language he's never even heard.
我有个想法
I've got one.
这是苗语  意思是  你们是群白痴
It means "You're a bunch of pathetic idiots" in Hmong.
也可能不是这意思
Or it doesn't.
但你们无从得知  因为你们不懂苗语
But you wouldn't know because none of you speak Hmong.
从另一方面看
Kid, on the other hand,
小孩子很会胡言乱语
is presumably fluent in gibberish.
他爷爷会苗语
The grandfather speaks Hmong.
他给我们翻译的
He translated.
他听到的是他想听到的话
He heard what he wanted to hear,
因为如果他孙子被附体了
'cause if his grandson really is possessed,
意味着他儿子也是
that means his son really is possessed,
这要远远好过
which is a giant step up
被人认定为凶残的精神病杀手
from being a sledgehammering psychopath.
不管是什么病  都导致了抽搐
Whatever it was preceded a seizure.
很显然是神经系统症状
It's obviously a neurological symptom.
是不是恶化到大脑的硬皮病呢
Scleroderma, advanced to the point that it's affecting his brain?
有趣
Interesting.
那么说我们应该着手...
So we should start treating...
有趣的是
Interesting that you keep
每次我说"有趣"你们总会上当
falling for it when I say "Interesting."
硬皮病的诊断太白痴了
The scleroderma part was idiotic.
如果是的话  会有皮肤症状
We'd have seen skin involvement.
我说有趣是因为
The interesting part is
你和朴克相互认同一个观点
that you and Park agree,
但是你们却没有眼神交流
but you're not able to look at each other.
我这不是在看她吗
I'm looking at her.
我也在看他
I'm looking at him.
很好  现在舔舔嘴唇
Good, now lick your lips.
拉斯马森脑炎
Rasmussen's encephalitis.
弥漫性灶性炎症
Diffuse spotty inflammation
会让脑自主神经中枢受损
could hit the autonomic centers of the brain.
这在苗语中的意思是  做核磁共振确诊
It's Hmong for "Get an MRI to confirm."
拉斯马森脑炎
Rasmussen's encephalitis.
他会没事的吧
But he'll be okay?
进行治疗的话  病情是可以控制的
With treatment, it's manageable.
这病能解释
And it explains all the things
他所有的症状吗
that have happened to him?
我们是这么认为的
We think so.
你们错了
You are wrong.
你们在浪费我孙子的时间
And you are wasting my grandson's time.
神经系统问题能导致病人
Neurological issues can cause a person
说别国的语言  或是说话带口音
to speak in tongues, speak with an accent.
他说的不是别国的语言
He wasn't speaking in tongues!
遇到压力的时候
In times of stress,
我们的感官会欺骗我们  让我们相信...
our senses can fool us into believing...
我深知科学和信仰的不同之处
I know the difference between science and faith,
当我儿子开始做那些
and when my son started having the same dreams
同我孙子一样的梦时  科学没能帮助他
my grandson is having, science couldn't help him.
对于你儿子遭受的精神疾病我很抱歉
I'm sorry if your son suffered from mental illness.
卡没有疯
Kao was not crazy.
他以前是个聪明  和善  快乐的人
He was bright, caring, happy,
直到噩梦降临
until the bad dreams came.
我不想眼看悲剧重演
I don't want to watch it happen again.
拜托别吓到小孩子
Please don't scare the boy.
那样是不会让病情好转的
It won't help him get better.
轴位中脑层面未见异常
Axial view of mid-brain level looks good.
开始观察丘脑
Moving on to thalamic.
昨晚我又做了个梦
I had another dream last night.
这次是关于你的
This time it was about you.
真的
Really?
瞧见没  是个人都应该是你这个反应
See, that's how you're supposed to react.
当一个女人告诉你  她梦见了你
When a woman tells you she's dreamt about you,
你应该会感到激动
you should be thrilled,
就算你对她没有感觉
even if you're not interested in her whatsoever.
知道吗  你真傻
You're an idiot, you know that?
我今晚绝对不会梦见你
Well, I definitely won't be dreaming about you tonight.
我很羡慕你们俩
I'm jealous of you two.
你们俩一个天一个地
You couldn't be more different,
但是你们心心相惜
and yet you have this good thing happening.
你们彼此有好感  支持对方
You support each other. You like each other.
别让豪斯毁了这份感觉
Don't let House screw it up.
我和他没这么大差别吧
We're not that different.
有的
Yeah, you are.
显然  你的很多本事
Apparently, there are some things about you
我都不知道
I don't know.
我在警察局服役过一年
I served one year in police unit.
这事儿你现在才和我这个当老公的说
And you're just telling your husband now?
移民局都不知道
Immigration doesn't know.
老公就更不需要知道了
No need for husband to know.
那个被恶魔附身的男孩怎么样了
What is happening to boy with demons?
磁共振检查显示正常
Absence of evidence on an MRI,
我的小组却以此认为是一切正常
which my team has mistaken for evidence of absence.
这我就不理解了
This is what I am not understanding:
为什么你可以相信暗物质的存在
How can you believe in dark matters
但却不信有恶灵存在
but not in dark spirits?
难道恶魔
Is--is the idea of demons
就跟希格斯玻色子有本质区别吗
so different than the Higgs boson?
我们看不见它本身
We can't see it, but we can see
但能看到它带来的影响
the impact of its presence.
我拿了你的物理学书籍
I borrowed your physics book.
在浴室里面看的
I read while in bathroom.
你是个神枪手
You're a dead-eye shot
而且还喜欢在蹲马桶时
and enjoy reading quantum physics
看量子力学
on the crapper?
我是洗澡时看的
I read in bathtub.
让人浮想联翩啊
Better image.
谢谢
Thank you.
医生说我的脑子有问题
The doctors say my brain is sick.
医生们尽了最大努力
Your doctors are trying their best,
但他们的方向错了
but they're not looking in the right place.
我知道  对于八岁的你
You know, I know this is a lot
很难承受这些
to put on an eight-year-old.
但你对于我们祖先的无视
But you have angered our ancestors
惹恼了他们
by ignoring them.
你记得怎样与他们交流吗
Now do you remember how to talk to them?
是的  就是这样
Yeah, that's right.
很好
Good.
现在闭上眼睛
Now close your eyes,
我们一起请求宽恕
and we will ask for forgiveness together.
你做得很好
You're doing good.
但还要付出更多
But we have to do more.
恶灵仍在空气中猖狂
The evil spirits are in the air,
而阻止它们的唯一方法
and the only way to stop them
就是停止呼吸
is by stopping the air.
你要勇敢
You have to be brave.
我并不想伤害你
I'm not trying to hurt you.
这是为了帮你
This will help you.
我坚信这一点
I know it will.
卢
Lue?
你还好吗
You okay?
我叫不醒他
I can't wake him up!
卢
Lue!
卢  你很安全
Lue, you're safe.
你在医院里
You're in the hospital.
别让爷爷靠近
Get Grandpa away!
他不在这  宝贝  那只是个梦
He's not here, honey. It was just a dream.
他想掐死我
He was choking me!
不  卢  那不是真的
No, Lue, it wasn't real.
是真的  他掐住了我的脖子
It was! He grabbed my neck!
之前没有这些淤青
Those bruises weren't there before.
他做了恶梦  而后出现了淤青
He had the dream, and then he had the bruising.
更有可能的解释是
More likely--
我说"有可能"  其实是指"理性"
And by "likely," I mean "rationally"--
前因后果搞反了
it's the other way around.
大脑感受到颈部疼痛
His brain felt the pain in his neck
就编了一场梦来解释它
and created the dream to explain it.
凝血障碍
Coagulopathy.
肺部问题造成凝血功能紊乱
Lung problems cause a clotting disturbance.
那他全身都会出现淤青
He would have bruises everywhere.
梦境会影响现实
Is it really preposterous
这个想法有那么荒谬吗
that dreams can have physical manifestations?
我真想拍你
Well, short answer is--
睡眠时的想法确实会造成生理变化
Thoughts during sleep can and do cause physical changes.
他说的对吗  朴克医生
Is that right, Dr. Park?
你今早醒来
Did you wake up this morning
是否感觉到生理变化
experiencing physical changes?
这跟医学有关
It's medically relevant.
她的梦没有任何意义
Her dream doesn't mean anything.
我们就不能用行动来承认这一点吗
Can we start acting like it doesn't mean anything?
行啊
Sure.
我们也可以不把墙当回事
We could also start acting like walls don't mean anything,
但这会让我们撞个鼻青脸肿
but then we'd hurt our noses.
你表现得如君子般坦荡
You've been taking the high road.
而不是利用这个明显的机会  取笑她
You haven't been teasing in an obviously teasable situation
因为你知道她的梦是有意义的
because you know it does mean something.
她讨厌这个梦因为这让她处于劣势
She hates the dream because it makes her feel vulnerable.
而你喜欢  是因为这让你有优越感
You love the dream because it makes you feel superior.
可怜的小姑娘
The poor lass who can't help
抵抗不了你的魅力
but fall sway to your charms.
而你正假装慷慨
And you're bestowing upon her
不与她计较这细枝末节
the gift of illusory irrelevance.
你能否悄悄告诉豪斯
Can you please hint to House
说你也做春梦了
that you had a sex dream?
我今天真心想治好病人
I'd really prefer not to get distracted
而不是被其他事分神
with trying to cure the patient today.
我拒绝透露我那些
I refuse to divulge my dreams
香艳的拉拉合体梦
about girl-on-girl loofa action.
淤青说明可能是贫血
The bruising could indicate anemia,
维生素C缺乏  甚至白血病
a Vitamin C deficiency, or even leukemia.
太奇怪了  你我做了相同的梦
That is so weird that you and I had the same dream.
我猜你的结尾也是
I assume yours also ends
我一边飘飘欲仙
with me achieving ecstasy while simultaneously
一边获得纽约马拉松季军
placing third in the New York City marathon.
季军
Third?
我有自知之明
I'm a realist.
肝衰竭可导致由肝性脑病引起的胡言乱语
Liver failure can cause gibberish from encephalopathy,
便秘  淤青和呼吸问题
constipation, bruising, and breathing problems.
肝纤维化变性会发生在此年龄的人身上
Hepatic fibrosis could hit someone at his age.
那就对肝下手
So let's hit his liver.
做活检
Get a biopsy.
角度向上倾斜一点
Angle a bit more superiorly.
他不断做这些噩梦
He keeps having these nightmares.
都成真了  真的伤害了他
That become real. They really hurt him.
我也不想相信
I don't want to believe that a nightmare
噩梦会成真  但...
can do that, but I--
我也不想相信
I'm struggling with it too,
不过这是可以用医学解释的
but these things can be explained medically.
但你们没有给出解释
But you haven't.
每个医生
Every doctor,
他们的每个想法
every idea they've had,
都是错的
it's been wrong.
肝活检结果出来了  准备开会
Liver biopsy's back. Team's about to meet.
又开始避免和我有眼神接触吗
Back to avoiding eye contact with me?
你又被豪斯影响了
House got to you again?
难道你想让我告诉你结果时
Want me to gaze longingly into your eyes
含情脉脉地看着你吗
as I tell you the test results?
我希望你把我当朋友来对待
I want you to treat me like a friend,
希望你不要在意
which means getting over the fact
你喜欢我多过我喜欢你
that you like me more than I like you.
你自负自夸的行为让我欲火焚身
Yeah, egotism and preening really turn me on.
可惜我对中性而自卑的人不感兴趣
Too bad I'm not attracted to androgyny and self-pity,
不然你就能如愿了
or you'd have it made.
因为任何还未被你
Because anyone who hasn't gotten wet
辣手摧花的女人
from your Petri dish of STDs,
就肯定是没自尊的
clearly has low self-esteem!
泼妇
Bitch.
混蛋
Dick!
你来吗
You coming?
你说话时为何嘴唇不动
Why didn't your lips move when you said that?
奇斯
Chase!
你来吗
You coming?
肝活检结果出来了
Liver biopsy's back.
我马上就来
I'll be right there.
肝纤维化变性活检结果呈阴性
Biopsy was negative for fibrosis.
就是说又一次
So once again,
你们还没找到病因
you don't know what's wrong?
能排除那些恶性病总是好的
It's always good to rule out the bad things.
医生
Doctors!
天哪
God!
他是不是
Was he?
是的
Yes.
-他悬空飘浮  -真酷
- He was levitating. - Cool.
我们能肯定的一件事就是
So the one thing we know for sure
他并没悬浮在空中
is he was not levitating.
他飘起来了
He was floating
离床六英寸高
6 inches off the bed.
他可能只是把背部拱起来而已
He could've just been arching his back off the bed.
没错  不过那样的话我就会到这里
Yes, but then I would have come into the room
报告说病人奇怪地
and reported that the patient
把背拱起来了
was weirdly arching his back off the bed.
但是那是他整个身体
It was his whole body.
他悬浮在空中
He was levitating.
太多疑问了...
So many questions...
第一个就是为什么奇斯要跟一个
Starting with why did Chase address his comment
当时没在屋里的人发表意见
to someone who wasn't even in the room?
骗术展示
Hocus pocus,
你们这些白痴注意我的脚
on my feet you idiots must focus.
那孩子不是魔术师
The kid's not a magician.
当然不是  他是可爱的助手
Of course not. He's the lovely assistant.
因为他那杀千刀的祖父在幕后操纵
'cause grandpa pig sticker is waving the wand.
第二个问题是...
Middling with...
奇斯是在回避陶博呢
is Chase trying to avoid Taub,
还是想以此证明
or is he trying to prove
他没有在回避朴克呢
that he's not avoiding Park?
我们检查了那床
We checked the bed.
没有什么板子或钢丝
There were no platforms or wires.
这并非戏法
This wasn't a trick.
破伤风可能导致肌肉强直
Tetanus could cause muscle rigidity.
也许他是被自己的脚跟和胳膊肘顶起来的
Maybe he was propped up by his heel and elbow.
但事实并非如此
Except he wasn't!
破伤风不会导致
Tetanus wouldn't cause
那种程度的呼吸困难
that kind of breathing difficulty.
最后的问题是...
And ending with...
如果奇斯不是在回避朴克
if Chase is trying not to avoid Park,
那为什么是今天而不是昨天
why is he doing this today and not yesterday?
但是低钙血症会导致呼吸困难
But hypocalcemia could,
而且在我们治疗便秘用的灌肠剂中
and the enema we administered to cure his constipation
含有大量的磷
had a high phosphorous load,
可能导致暂时性低钙血症
which could make him transiently hypocalcemic.
这个说法有点勉强
It's a long shot, but at least
但至少还是理智的判断
it has the benefit of being rational.
给他补充电解质  开始用β受体阻滞剂
Go pump up his electrolytes and start beta-blockers.
对朴克来说是好消息
And good news for Park:
我想奇斯做了个和你有关的春梦
I think Chase had a sex dream about you.
就是场梦而已
Dreams don't mean anything.
我不明白  你们做的一切都没用
I don't know. Nothing you've done has helped.
如果我们不治疗  他再次癫痫发作
If we don't start and he has another seizure,
就可能造成永久性的神经损伤
the neurological damage could be permanent.
我的公公
My father-in-law.
他认为召唤仪式
He thinks the calling ceremony
没有成功是因为卢不在场
didn't work because Lue wasn't there.
你觉得他是对的吗
And you think he's right?
我不知道
I don't know.
不好意思  但我们不可能同意
I'm sorry, but there's no way
他在你儿子的病房内
we can allow him to perform an exorcism
进行驱邪仪式
in your son's hospital room.
那我就带他回家
Then I will have to take him home.
一天前你还因为
A day ago, you were insulted
我误解你相信迷信而感到受辱
I'd even think you might believe that stuff,
而现在你宁可停止一切治疗
and now you're willing to stop all treatment,
只为了尝试驱邪吗
so you can try it?
也许翔对卡的看法是对的
Maybe Xang was right about Kao.
我爱的那个人并非恶魔
The man I loved wasn't evil
他本人从未行过凶
and would never do what he did.
他只是...被附身了
He was...possessed.
现在得把我儿子的灵魂找回来
And my son needs his soul back.
为什么不行呢
Why not?
只要他不给孩子喂什么东西
As long as he doesn't feed the kid anything
或是在他皮肤上涂一些我们无法
or put anything on his skin that we haven't
证明是否有害的东西  应该就没问题了
verified is harmless, what's the problem?
我同意
I agree.
既然我们要制定这个
And since we're establishing a new policy
病急乱投医的新政策
of "What the hell, we'll try anything,"
我想雇夏奇拉来边跳肚皮舞
I'd like to hire Shakira to belly dance
边演唱《Waka Waka》[南非世界杯主题曲]
while singing Waka Waka.
只要你能获得他母亲和夏奇拉的同意就行
As long as you get the mom and Shakira to consent.
这和请牧师或是
It's no different than having a priest
拉比[犹太法师]来进行守夜祷告没什么区别
or rabbi lead a prayer vigil.
他母亲只是吓坏了迷茫了
The mom is scared and confused
竭尽全力的寻求能带给她希望的办法
and desperate for anything that'll give her hope.
没错
True.
不过从长远看  我认为让我们的律师
But in the long run, I think you'll be happier
声称她举止失当会让你感觉好些
having our lawyer declare her unfit.
那你就不会批准凌驾于科学之上的迷信行为了
That way you won't be ratifying superstition over science,
我也会继续在这工作
and I'll still be working here.
那为什么会让我感觉好些
And why would that make me happier?
你哪也不会去
You're not going anywhere,
我们也不是在批准别人的信仰
and we're not "ratifying" their beliefs,
我们这是尊重他们
we're respecting them.
你知道这也许会涉及到动物祭祀吧
You do realize it may involve animal sacrifice.
住在这种遍布玻璃墙的医院里的人
People who live in glass hospitals
不该进行驱邪活动
should not throw exorcisms.
我会跟他母亲谈的
I'll talk to the mother.
我并不是不给他医学治疗
I don't want to deny him the medicine,
我只是...
I just...
想确保我尝试了一切可能的方法
want to make sure I try everything I can.
我理解
I understand that,
但你也要理解我们这里是医院
but you have to understand that we're a hospital,
并非寺庙
not a temple.
那我就带他去别的地方
Then I'll take him elsewhere.
不  你不能
No, you won't.
他病了  我们不能让他离开这里
He's sick. We can't let him leave here.
不好意思  你确实别无选择
I'm sorry, you really have no choice.
我跟律师聊过了
I spoke to a lawyer.
他告诉我只要我没有对你们的治疗方案说不
He told me as long as I wasn't saying no to your treatment,
你们也不能否定我的信仰
you couldn't say no to my religion.
给我24小时
Give me 24 hours.
我今天收到这封信
This came in the mail today!
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我早该告诉你
I should've told you.
告诉我什么
Told me what?
我不明白
I don't understand.
那信写的什么
What's the letter?
是我波兰的叔叔寄来的
It's from my uncle in Poland.
我阿姨卢巴  两个月前被送到疗养院去了
My aunt Luba, they put her in nursing home two months ago!
太糟了
That's too bad.
我母亲  我每周和她打两次电话
My mother, I talk to her twice a week
她从没跟我说过这事儿
and she never even mentioned it.
她怎么想的  觉得我承受不了吗
Wh--what does she think? That I can't handle?
我已经29岁了  不是个孩子了
I am 29 years old! I am not a child!
你今晚要出去吗
Were you going out tonight?
我可以留下
I could stay.
他还是呼吸困难
He's still barely breathing.
卢
Lue?
你感觉如何
How you feeling?
感觉好些吗
Any stronger?
卢  听得到我说话吗
Lue, can you hear me?
-怎么了  -我不确定
- What's wrong? - I'm not sure.
卢  我要你握住我的手
Lue, I need you to squeeze my hand.
他没反应  给我50毫升50%D-葡萄糖
He's not responding. Get me an amp of d50!
你们又错了吗
You were wrong again?
我要叫他爷爷来
I'm calling his grandfather.
布鲁格达综合征和长Q-T综合征
Genetic tests for brugada and long QT variants
的遗传学检测都呈阴性
came back negative.
会不会是颈动脉瘤
What about a carotid aneurysm?
我们应该做个血管造影
We should do an angiogram.
他的颈动脉搏动正常
He's got normal carotid pulses.
管他呢
Who cares?
他母亲都放弃了  我为什么要在乎
Mom's given up, why shouldn't I?
不好意思
I'm sorry,
我们不是连白痴都治吗  因为我认为...
do we not treat idiots? Because I thought--
她的孩子漂浮了
Her kid levitated.
如果我女儿也这样
That happens to my girl,
我会扩大我的诊断范围
I'm expanding my diagnostic horizons.
所以我们更该关门大吉
All the more reason why we should shut down.
现在治好这孩子
We cure this kid now,
功劳会被疯癫祖父和他那套鬼把戏抢走的
crazy grandpa and his magic beads get all the credit.
你几时开始关心功劳归谁了
And since when do you care about credit?
我几时开始关心这孩子了
Since when do I care about this kid?
我关心的不过是
All I care about is sending mommy
培养出相信真理的妈妈
out into the world having faith in faith.
孩子不如死了算了
Kid's better off dead.
等她认识到求神无用  我们再谈
As soon as she's done appeasing the Gods, let's talk.
会不会是川崎病
What about Kawasaki?
可以解释不规则心音
It explains the irregular heartbeat,
呼吸窘迫和癫痫发作
respiratory distress, and seizures.
症状吻合
It fits.
那么他需要冠状动脉搭桥手术
Which means he needs a coronary bypass.
不可能是川崎病
It can't be Kawasaki.
心脏超声检查应该能看到
Echo would have shown it.
但是动脉导管未闭
But a patent ductus arteriosis...
不可能是小儿先天性心脏病
It can't be a PDA.
他又不是婴儿
He's not an infant,
而且八岁了还没有过任何症状
nor has he had any symptoms for eight years.
说不定有过
Maybe he has.
说不定他得过动脉导管感染
Maybe he had an infected ductus,
而被我们无意中使用的抗生素治疗了
which we inadvertently treated with antibiotics.
所以无证据倒成了证据存在的证明
So no evidence is evidence of evidence?
我只是说  可以这样推理
I'm just saying, it's consistent.
只有十亿分之一的几率
It's a billion-to-one.
也就是说  世界上有七个人
Which means there's seven people in the world
符合此诊断
who fit the diagnosis.
不是要找一百个嘛
I thought we were looking for 100.
或许小儿心脏病发病率比我们所知要高
Well, maybe PDA is more common than we thought.
像你这种白痴医生
With idiot doctors like you...
你错了
You're wrong.
治疗方法是布洛芬
But the treatment's just ibuprofen.
闭合畸形的动脉导管
Closes the malformed duct.
最坏的可能不过是他不见好转而已
Worst-case scenario, he just doesn't get better.
不  最坏的可能不过是你惹急了我
No, worst-case scenario is you piss me off...
你不让我们救一个八岁孩子
You're not gonna let us save an eight-year-old
就因为不想多一个人皈依宗教吗
because one more person might embrace religion?
这里有人认为我的诊断正确吗
Does anyone here think my diagnosis is right?
那么我决定
Well, then I have decided,
仅此一天  尊重你们的意见
for today only, to respect your opinions.
我们完全依照你们的诊断进行治疗
We will proceed according to your diagnosis and nothing else.
这是命令
That's an order.
好运
Good luck.
得把他排上手术日程
We need to put him on the O.R. Schedule.
血压正在下降
His B.P.'s dropping.
他不行了  叫急救
He's crashing. Call a code!
你必须停下
You need to stop this!
我给他用布洛芬
I'm giving him the ibuprofen.
晚饭马上就好
Dinner's almost ready.
我今晚就喝酒吧  谢谢
I think I'll stick with the fluids tonight, thanks.
你怎么闷闷不乐的
Why are you sulking?
我没有
I'm not sulking.
那是我搞错了
Oh, my mistake.
孩子濒临死亡  要么是信仰害的
Either religion is killing a kid,
要么是我害的
or I am.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
丈夫辛劳一天  我来帮他放松
Comforting my husband after a bad day.
如果你不喜欢
If this is not what you want,
我就回去准备晚餐
I go back to making dinner.
我才不接
I'm not gonna answer that.
聪明
Oh, smart man.
吵得老娘性致全无了
This is killing mood.
美国民政局
U.S. Citizenship!
我来接
I'll get it.
我是豪斯夫人
This is Mrs. House,
拜托说点儿好消息
please give good news,
我好回去和丈夫继续爱爱
so my husband and I can go back to sex.
太好啦
Budmo! Is fantastic!
你们给我发了多少封通知函
How many notices you send me?
好吧  我自己去取入籍证书
O-okay, I.. I come pick up naturalization certificate.
多谢来电
Thank you for calling.
对不起
I'm sorry.
亚当斯医生  陶博医生
Dr. Adams, Dr. Taub?
各项生命指数都在回升  他稳定下来了
His vitals are improving. He's stabilizing.
他会好起来的
He's gonna be okay.
驱邪起作用了
It worked.
不是的
Um, no, it didn't.
陈夫人  我使用的药物
Mrs. Cheng, the medicine I administered
是对卢的心脏进行长效治疗
was a long-shot treatment for Lue's heart,
帮助他的是药物
but that's what's helping him.
布洛芬
Ibuprofen?
不是用来治头痛的吗
That's for headaches.
我知道听起来难以置信
I know it seems hard to believe,
但是确有其事
but it's true.
我也知道这对你来说难以置信
And I know this seems hard for you to believe.
亲爱的
Honey...
爷爷是对的
Grandpa was right.
他救了你
He saved you.
我们之前以为两件事都不可能
There were two things we thought were impossible.
其中之一是可能的
One of them wasn't.
就这样了
That's all we know.
我厉害吗
Was I good?
说明不了什么
Doesn't mean anything.
我被心理暗示了  会做那种梦是必然的
Idea got planted. It was probably inevitable.
能说明一些事情
It means something.
什么
What?
这不明摆着嘛
Well, it could mean the obvious,
你想要我
that you want some of this.
你几时能明白那种眼神很伤人的
When will you learn that that look is insulting?
或者能说明  我们彼此有好感
Or it could just mean that we like each other.
我古怪  你帅气
I'm weird, and you're pretty,
可是我们心心相印  有安全感
but we connect. We feel safe.
相互信任
We trust each other.
可能吧
Maybe.
只是验证下我的理论
Just testing my theory.
亚当斯违抗了我
Adams defied me.
这世界又多了一个偏执狂
There's one more zealot in the world.
多米尼卡搬走了
And Dominika moved out.
她风趣  艳丽
She was fun. She was hot.
修好了我的搅拌器
She fixed my blender.
不是比喻
That is not a metaphor.
你认不认识好点的冒牌离婚律师
You know any good fake divorce lawyers?
我竟然如此难过  还真是奇怪
I am surprisingly depressed by this.
我得了癌症
I have cancer.
你那天对我是有些过分
You were a little short with me the other day.
确实需要借口
You do need an excuse.
但癌症有点儿过了
Cancer may be overplaying it.
胸腺瘤二期
Stage II Thymoma.
我想等确诊之后再告诉你
I didn't want to tell you until I had it confirmed.
今天上午刚收到化验结果
I got the tests back this morning.
我得了癌症  豪斯
I have cancer, House.